Guide to the Randolph C. Sailer Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Randolph C. Sailer Papers
1932-1982
RG 148
Yale University Divinity School Library
2
(4 boxes)
Correspondence, reports, and printed material document Sailer's years as an educational missionary at Yenching University as well as his reflections about his years in China and his continued involvement with Christianity in China and U.S./ China relations. Randolph Clothier Sailer was an American Presbyterian missionary in China from 1923 to 1950, serving as a professor of psychology at Yenching University in Beijing. He taught at Forman Christian College in Lahore, Pakistan from 1953 to 1958.
Sailer, Randolph C. (Randolph Clothier), 1898-1981
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Agnes Sailer.
Biographical / Historical
1898 Born in Philadelphia, PA, son of Dr. and Mrs. T.H.P. Sailer.
1919 B.A., Princeton
1923-1950 Appointed by the Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. as a missionary to China; began teaching career as professor of Psychology at Yenching University in Peking
1925 Married Louise Egbert, a graduate of Smith who in 1923 was appointed by the ABCFM to be the director of the Religion Department of Yenching Women's College. They had three surviving children; George (1926), Henry (1929) and James (1931).
1931 Ph.D. in Educational Psychology at Columbia.
1941 Sailer's wife and children returned to the U.S., but he was interned at Weihsien and the family was separated for almost three years.
1945 Sailers returned to Chengtu.
1950 Left China in August.
1952-1953 Trained at Carl Rogers Counseling Center in Chicago.
1953-1958 Both Louise and Randolph teaching at Forman Christian College in Lahore, Pakistan.
1962-1973 Taught at Swarthmore, Morganwood, PA and Miles College, Birmingham, Alabama (1963)
1973 Returned to China with Louise and son Henry for a month long visit.
197x Became involved with United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia and United Presbyterian Church regarding annuities for Yenching teachers and the China Claims Committee.
1981 Jul 11 Died at the age of 82 at the Friends House, a Quaker retirement home in Sandy Springs, MD.
Scope and Contents
The Sailer papers document Sailer's years as a missionary/teacher at Yenching University as well as his reflections about those years in China and his continued involvement with Christianity in China and U.S./China relations throughout his life. Additional materials related to Sailer are found in YDSL Record Group No. 11, Archives of the United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia.
The Chronological Files of Series I are divided into two sections. The section on Sailer's Yenching years includes correspondence, reports and printed material concerning his work in China. The material is sketchy for 1932-41 but the years 1941-43 and 1946-50 are documented. Much of the correspondence in the Post-Yenching section is with friends with whom Sailer served in China. The transcript of an oral history interview conducted in 1979 is included.
The original titles of the folders in Series II, Subject Files, have been maintained. The subjects of China/U.S. relations, China and Christianity, and the UBCHEA files dealing with China claims and annuities are particularly well documented. Other files relate to different interests and activities of RCS. In addition to correspondence, the files contain reports, printed material and working papers.
The Writings of Series III include one book by Sailer and one book about him. Personality and Everyday Behavior by Sailer (1935) was the text used in his Yenching courses. The Audiotapes of Series IV include an interview of Sailer by Katherine Ni, a former student who planned to write a biography of RCS.
Arrangement
I. Chronological Files, 1932-1982, n.d.
II. Subject Files, 1950-1981
III. Writings, 1935, n.d.
IV. Audiotapes, 1980, 1982
Missions -- China; Sailer, Randolph C. (Randolph Clothier), 1898-1981; Forman Christian College (Lahore, Pakistan); Yanjing da xue
- Chronological Files, 1932-1982, n.d.; Series I
  - Yenching years, 1932-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Post-Yenching years, 1951-1982, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5-10)
  - Post-Yenching years, 1951-1982, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
- Subject Files, 1950-1981; Series II
  - Blacks (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - China/ U.S. relations: correspondence, reports, and printed material (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - China/ U.S. relations: writings, notes, and fragments (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - China/ U.S. relations: "China Revisited" - ms. by Michael Lindsay, comments and correspondence (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - China/ U.S. relations: Taiwan (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - China/ U.S. relations: "Ten Suggestions for Working to Understand China and America Better" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Christianity in China (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Communication (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Communism, Vietnam (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Delinquency (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Missionaries (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Pakistan (Box 3, Folder 25-28)
  - Philosophy/ Psychology (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Teaching (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia: policy statements, working papers, printed material (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - United Board for Christian Higher Education in Asia: Sailer's drafats of his reponse to China claims policy (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Writings, 1935, n.d.; Series III
  - Personality and Everyday Behavior by RCS, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Dr. Sailer in China (258 p. book in Chinese, with illustrations), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Audiotapes, 1980, 1982; Series IV
  - "An Informal Gathering at Friends House", 1982? (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Sailer - On Religion and Philosophy" - Interview by Katherine Ni, a former student who planned to write a biography of RCS, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 37)